SARA VAGNARELLI

Software Engineer

- @ saravagnarelli@gmail.com
 github.com/saravgn
- Sydney, NSW, Australia saravagnarelli.com
- in linkedin.com/in/engsaravagnarelli/ +61 427 487 300
 Work authorization: Australian Permanent Resident

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer II

Amazon

April 2021 - Present

Sydney, Australia

Senior Software Engineer

Deckard Technologies

Aug 2018 - Jan 2021

♀ Sydney, Australia

Deckard designs and develops analytical reporting systems using modern deep data mining, machine learning and predictive analytical algorithms to ensure that local governments have the insights to return equity of obligations back to the community and sustain healthy revenue to support smart city growth.

- Wrote AWS CloudFormation scripts to build CodePipelines for CI/CD and ETL. Designed scalable and economic data pipeline process that ensures reliability and consistency for a large number of data feeds. Created Datadog Dashboard and Alerts through CloudFormation scripts to analyse log stream.
 - AWS Python (TDD), Docker, boto3, CloudFormation, Jinja2, CloudWatch, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, Batch, S3, Glue(basic PySpark), Athena, EC2, Selenium, Jira, Github.
- Developed a full-stack website mainly the back-end to create a
 unified view of output of the data analytic processes and enable us,
 data analysts, to quickly evaluate results and prove our algorithms.
 Techstack: Python, Postgres, Rest-ful APIs, AWS-Cognito for user
 authentication, AWS API Gateway, Flask, React, Wireframe,
 LucidChart.

Contributed to React Redux Datatable library https://github.com/sean-ww/react-redux-datatable/graphs/contributors.

Software Engineer

Qualcomm ESGDA - Engineering Service Group Data Analytics

M Nov 2016 - May 2018

♀ Sydney, Australia

The Engineering Services Group Data Analytics team builds creative and reliable big data solutions that add value across Qualcomm. These solutions range from but are not limited to wireless communications, intellectual property and financial analysis.

- Accumulated significant experience in developing performant, efficient Python code, applying a test-driven methodology to guarantee the correctness of the code after modifications
- **Profiling and debugging** of performance related problems both in Python code and in **SQL** database code.
- Development of REST-ful APIs to access information and allow data exchange between multiple components of larger systems (Flask, HTML, CSS)
- Automated regression test suite which exercised 95%+ of the codebase using PyTest and unittest.
- Used Jenkins and Docker for continuous integration and GitHub for Revision Control. Followed an agile methodology and participation in weekly code reviews. Used Jira, Confluence.

SUMMARY

I have Bachelor's and Master's Degree in Computer Science and 5 years of working experience as Software Engineer. I enjoy developing and experimenting with new technology but I prefer to be technology-agnostic and find the best solution to the problem. I am looking for a challenging role that drives change and provides opportunities for career development.

EDUCATION

M.S. in Computer Engineering Roma Tre University, Italy

May 2015 Oct 2012 - May 2015

B.S. in Computer Engineering Roma Tre University, Italy

Deep Learning Nanodegree Udacity

🛗 Jan 2018 - Present

Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree

Udacity

May 2016 - Sept 2016

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Dog-Breed Classifier

github.com/saravgn/dogbreedclassifier Designed and trained a CNN to identify dog breeds. Applied Transfer Learning to improve the model. **Keras, NumPy, VGG-16, ResNet-50, Scikit-learn**

Sentiment Classification github.com/saravgn/sentimentclassifier Predict sentiment from movie reviews. NumPv. Scikit-Learn

Predicting Bike Sharing Data github.com/saravgn/bikesharingpred Built and trained a Neural Network from scratch to predict the number of bike-share users on a given day. NumPy

EXPERIENCE

Consultant / Software Engineer

Accenture

math Sep 2015 - Apr 2016

Rome, Italy

Ministry of Economy and Finance - Indoor Navigation System
Joined Accenture as a graduate software engineer. My first role was as a
part of a consulting team working with the Italian MEF (Ministry of
Economy and Finance) developing an Indoor Navigation System this
included producing a feasibility study evaluating cost and time

Member of in-house software development team

Joined in-house software development team working in Java and SQL for a variety of clients. My role was primarily optimising in-house process including coordinating testing activities and automating processes execution

Research Fellow

New York University

Mov 2014 - May 2015

New York, NY, USA

Conducted a joint research project with Full Professor Chee Yap on autonomous navigation and mapping in GPS-denied environments

- Designed and developed an algorithm for **drones quadcopter** on using the onboard monocular camera to automatically build a reliable map of the area in which the drone is flying. **VISUAL SLAM**.
- Designed and developed image processing APIs in C/C++ for objects recognition and used OpenCV (Open Source Computer Vision Library)

recognition and used **Opency** (Open Source Computer Vision *Librar*

Software Engineering Intern

Roma Tre University

Dec 2011 - May 2012

Rome, Italy

Designed and implemented software for the **geolocation** of radar maps in order to individuate the composition of the underground using **Android** platform

Github Github

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

- SheHacks-Sydney 2019: Awarded for Best DataScience App https://www.linkedin.com/in/engsaravagnarelli/dactivity/
- CLOUDERA, Data Analyst Fundamentals of data ETL (extract, transform, load), ingestion, and processing with Hadoop tools and how Pig, Hive, and Impala improve productivity for typical analysis tasks.
- C++ programming course
- Academic Language Certificates
 English: TOEFL-IELTS-PTE-BULATS-FIRST-KET-PET.

 Spanish: DELE Cervantes, Camino Barcelona

LANGUAGES/HOBBIES

- 3D printing ED-209
- Arduino 4-wheel Robot
- Amazon AWS Dash Buttons

English, Italian Spanish



Team: Volleyball, Dance, Karate **Instruments:** Piano and Flute